<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Bessie Wong</title>
    <link>https://bessiewong.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://bessiewong.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://bessiewong.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://bessiewong.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media: Instagram</title>
      <link>https://bessiewong.github.io/post/socialmedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bessiewong.github.io/post/socialmedia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Willow Lash Lab Posts February 2018-May 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bessiewong.github.io/images/IMG_4885.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wwl&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bessiewong.github.io/images/IMG_4883.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wwl&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bessiewong.github.io/images/IMG_4886.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wwl&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bessiewong.github.io/images/IMG_4884.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wwl&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: 5 Ways to Avoid the Mid-Day Crash</title>
      <link>https://bessiewong.github.io/post/blog-co-op/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bessiewong.github.io/post/blog-co-op/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bessiewong.github.io/images/bessie2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Vancouver skyline&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s two hours past lunchtime, and you’re starting to feel it - you slowly start to doze off. The mid-day crash has got you feeling all the feels. Sleepiness is a natural response of our bodies after a meal as the digestion process occurs. While we’ve all been there, you don’t want to make it a habit and hinder your work productivity- especially while you are on a co-op work term!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking of curling up in your cubicle? Here are 5 ways (caffeine-free!) to keep energized throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-spice-up-your-hydration-by-adding-a-slice-of-lemon-lime-or-mint-to-your-water&#34;&gt;1. Spice up your hydration by adding a slice of lemon, lime, or mint to your water&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know?  Being 3-4% dehydrated can lower your work performance by up to 50%! Which can lead you to become less focused and sleepy when the afternoon hits.  Adding a slice of lemon gives you a boost of vitamin C while adding lime can improve digestion after a meal. If you are not a fan of citrus fruits, a cucumber or a mix of berries might do the trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-get-some-fresh-air&#34;&gt;2. Get some fresh air&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canada has some of the worlds’ cleanest air and what better way to enjoy it than to go outside! If your coop is located in Downtown Vancouver- great! Head out to waterfront to view spectacular North Vancouver across the water or to Yaletowns’ harbour area along the seawall. When you’re in sync with mother nature and seeing the vibrant colours of Vancouver, take a moment to breathe. Ahhh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-organize-your-surroundings&#34;&gt;3. Organize your surroundings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The places we work, sleep and eat all play a role in our productivity and engagement. De-clutter your desk space and use office supplies like sticky notes and folders to colour coordinate your things. Use a yellow tint screen shader to limit the effects of a harsh computer screen on your eyes. If you’ve got an ergonomic desk, stand up to work during intervals of times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-buy-an-office-plant-pet&#34;&gt;4. Buy an office plant pet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indoor plants work to remove toxins and help humidify the room.  There are plenty of options ranging from those that do well in low light to full sun.  Make sure to figure out what would be best for your desk location.  My personal all-around favorite that I kept at my desk was an aloe vera and small succulent- both that required minimal watering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-exercise-during-your-lunch-hour&#34;&gt;5. Exercise during your lunch hour&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barre, spin, and gym classes are perfect for adding into your daily schedule if your office is in downtown Vancouver. &lt;a href=&#34;https://classpass.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Classpass&lt;/a&gt; offers tons of drop-ins to studios for up to 70% off studio price. I frequently went to conditioning classes from Pure Barre and free yoga classes from the wellness room at SFU Harbour centre. If you’re not close to a studio, find some green space outside and follow a youtube video or simply take the time to relax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow these five things, and you’re bound to have a more energized space throughout the day. I worked at the &lt;a href=&#34;www.recbc.ca&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Real Estate Council of BC&lt;/a&gt; for eight months, and one of my favourite things to enjoy was beautiful Downtown Vancouver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the original post &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfu.ca/olc/blog/co-op/5-ways-avoid-mid-day-crash-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Speaking between two cultures: An interview</title>
      <link>https://bessiewong.github.io/post/blog-speaking-between-two-languagesan-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bessiewong.github.io/post/blog-speaking-between-two-languagesan-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bessiewong.github.io/images/pxfuel.com-id-xppht.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Conversation Partners in conversation about language, learning, and SFU.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lib.sfu.ca/about/branches-depts/slc/eal/conversation/registration-form-eal-esl-students&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SLC Conversation Partners Program&lt;/a&gt;  pairs EAL students with volunteer peers. Conversation partners then meet on a weekly basis throughout the semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, SLC Peer  &lt;strong&gt;Bessie W.&lt;/strong&gt; interviewed two of her conversation partners, Bin and Dan, to hear their unique perspectives on the program and their experiences at SFU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bin&lt;/strong&gt;  is an Economics student who arrived in Canada three years ago from the Guangdong province of China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan&lt;/strong&gt;  is an Interactive Arts and Technology student from the SiChuan province of China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What motivated you to participate in the SLC Conversation Partners Program?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan:&lt;/strong&gt;  For international students, language is the first challenge, especially for first year students. There is no other way for us to know the cultural differences and having a conversational partner will help us to understand. A lot of the English we learned in high school is not applicable to what we actually say in an English-speaking country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bin:&lt;/strong&gt; I was planning to sign up for co-op next semester and wanted someone to practice my speaking skills with because there will be lots of situations where I will need to speak my opinions, such as during interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your biggest takeaway from the program so far? What did you enjoy the most?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan:&lt;/strong&gt;  Before attending this program, I was not comfortable speaking in discussions and teamwork and I was fearful that they wouldn’t take my opinions seriously. Now, I have the courage to speak out and express myself, especially among English speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bin:&lt;/strong&gt; I was provided with a great opportunity to practice and improve my English speaking skills. My peer was like a mentor to me because she was patient with me, and it was an open space where I could ask questions. We even talked about the past election that occurred!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where do you see yourself in five years? Staying in Canada or elsewhere?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan:&lt;/strong&gt;  I hope to graduate and find a job here. My goal is to make a living by myself, with no financial support from my parents. My own mindset has changed a lot after living in Canada, so I might not follow the culture back in China. For example, people doing business in China often talk indirectly when giving feedback or criticism, but I prefer people to be direct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bin:&lt;/strong&gt;  For myself, I would ideally like to work for 2-3 years after graduation and then move back to China. Family is important to me and that is a motivational factor for me. It is where I feel the most at home, where I belong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some of the struggles of living as an EAL student at SFU/ in Canada?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan:&lt;/strong&gt; During my first year as a Fraser International College student, I couldn’t understand the academic language from the professors. I would question their processes because of the cultural difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bin:&lt;/strong&gt; Academically, listening is hard because we end up falling more behind and have to make up with extra study time in order to fully understand the material. Participation is a big deal in universities in Canada, so we must speak up in order to earn marks, but sometimes we might be judged or critiqued from our lack of English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some things that you would like non-EAL students to know?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan:&lt;/strong&gt; This program is not just for learning and improving the English language, but through language we can learn a lot of people’s ideologies and their thoughts, and how they engage in their ideas. We both learn from each others’ perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bin:&lt;/strong&gt;  Learning a language is a continuous process, it takes time and as much as you learn it, you also need to use it. The most important thing is that you need to find a real interest so that you can practice. Maybe that is watching a TV show or reading a book in that language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thank you both for sharing your thoughts and experiences!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;strong&gt;Bessie W.&lt;/strong&gt; has been an EAL Peer at the Student Learning Commons since 2015. She enjoys learning about various cultures and languages around the world. She is a Communications student with an interest in writing and social media marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the original post &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lib.sfu.ca/about/branches-depts/slc/incommon/conversation-partners-interview&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
